CHRISTIAN ANTONIO AVILA SAUCEDO

SOFTWARE - ENGINEER



(+52) 618 159 5214



christian-antonio-avila-saucedo-9a83691aa

https://christianavilacv.netlify.app

INFORMATION

Location: Durango, México. Languages: English (B2+)

Spanish (Native)

EDUCATION

(B.S) SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Universidad Politécnica de Durango 2017 - 2020

<u>CERTIFICATIONS</u> IBM API Connect v2018 API Skills

Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC) SCRUMstudy-Accreditation Body for Scrum and Agile

ABOUT ME

I'm a passionate digital experience creator with a focus on crafting beautiful, userfriendly interfaces (UI/UX) and developing responsive apps. My expertise extends to design patterns and writing clean code for robust, SEOfriendly architectures. I'm not just a software developer; I'm an architect of digital experiences, dedicated to excellence in every project I undertake.

SKILLS

















Webpack



NextJS



MvSQL

NodeJS

👙 Java

Unity

Jest

◆ Git Postman

IBM MQ

AstroJS

EXPERIENCE

FRONT-END DEVELOPER - M6CONNECT

Omaha, Nebraska, United States

AUG 2023 - CURRENT

I playing an essential role in the creation of widgets for a software as a service (SaaS) application and process automation with regular expressions (REGEX) using react and typescript. I'm also improving the efficiency of the apps and performing **unit testing**.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER MID / API MANAGER - NEXTIA

Mexico City, Mexico JUN 2022 - JUN 2023

I was **developing** apps for our clients and for the Government, these are developed with React, Typescript and testing with Jest and Cypress following the SCRUM model, I am also used MQ - IBM and Java as an intermediary Backend for asynchronously queueing requests and creating APIs.

Also, I lead the development of a massive application for Currie & Brown.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER - VENN PLATFORM

Mexico City, Mexico

MAY 2021 - MAY 2022

I was redoing some modules for a **startup** using **React**, **Redux**, **Context** & **Axios**. I corrected the design of multiple interfaces making proper use of UX, among the new features are: a coupon system and a dashboard with charts and gradient styles using chart.js and some smooth animations using gsap. I made unit testing and also updated components to typescript.

FREELANCE VIDEOGAME DEVELOPER - MATTE

Mexico City, Mexico MAR 2020 - APR 2020

I was in charge of refactoring part of the AR app with Unity for the new carmodel 'NISSAN frontier 2021' for NISSAN company, I programmed new functionalities such as multilanguage and the creation of new kinematics, all using a high level of OOP.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER - UJED

Durango, Mexico MAY 2019 - MAR 2020

I developed the 'Durango state language school university' (CELE) website using Vue, Tailwind and Sass, developing a user management system, allowing users to enroll in various courses. I consumed API's to allow the user to pay for course registrations, I consumed Django / PostgreSQL API's to allow the user to register. I worked with **scrum** and using **webpack** in the project.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - CENTRO DE SALUD #2

Durango, Mexico

JAN 2018 - MAY 2018

I developed an inventory control and patient registration system, a registry for the control of medicines, an inventory system for a hospital using MySQL, C# and WPF.





🥸 🖟 📆 🦓 🗸 🔥

🥸 🖒 Ts 💃 📵 🗸 ♦





























A D



